Guide to the Hendrik Edelman papers, 1969-1974.
Edelman, Hendrik papers, 1969-1974
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hendrik Edelman papers, 1969-1974.
13-1-1887
Cornell University Libraries.Assistant Director.
13.4 cubic ft.
Subject files
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Alphbetical files of Assistant Director Hendrik Edelman concerning collection development.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Hendrik Edelman served as Assistant Director of the Cornell University Libraries from 1969 to 1979, and then became University Librarian at Rutgers University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Alphbetical files of Assistant Director Hendrik Edelman concerning collection development. Also, files relating to research on his book, Dutch-American Bibliography 1693-1794, a descriptive catalog of Dutch-language books, pamphlets, and almanacs printed in America, 1974; research, consulting, teaching, and other professional papers relating to immigrant presses in America and to library collection development; videos of a Pennsylvania State Library teleconference on collection development; and publications by Edelman.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Edelman, Hendrik.
Subjects:
Collection development.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- A - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Acquisitions, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- B - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Budget and Acquisitions, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Business Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- C - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Catalog, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CATS Committee, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Circulation, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Reprints Committee, Center for Urban Development, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- D - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- E - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Engineering Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- F - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Fine Arts Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- G - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Gift and Exchange, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- H - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- History of Science, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- I - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- ILR, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- J - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- K - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- L - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Law Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- M - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Maps, Micrtotext and Newspaper Department, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Mann Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Manuscripts and Archives, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Music Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- N - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Near Eastern Studies (Semitics), 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- O - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- P - General, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Physical Sciences Library, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Q - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- R - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Rare Books, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Reference, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- S - General, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Serials Department, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- T - General, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- U - General, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Uris Library, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- V - General, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- W - General, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- X, Y, Z - General, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Library Association, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Library Association, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Human Relations Area Files, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Baker and Taylor Survey Office, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Center for Research Libraries, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Acquisitions
  - Americas, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Asia, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - South East Asia, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Australia, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Austria, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Canada, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - England - "A-L", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - England - "M-Z", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - France, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Germany, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Israel, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Finland - Ireland; Europe, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Italy, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Lebanon, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Liechtenstein, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Netherlands, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Africana Center, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Harrassowitz, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Nardechia, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Nijhoff, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Switzerland, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Poland - Turkey, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Philippines, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Russia, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - US - "A-B", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - US - "C", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - US - "D-G", 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - US - "H", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - US - "I-L", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - US - "M", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - US - "N-Q", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - US - "R", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - US - "S", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - US - "T-Z", 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Kaser, David, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Research notes, Dutch American bibliography (Box 4)
  Includes notes, reprints, copies and "A Guide to the Archives of the Netherlands Museum,Holland, Michigan, 1978"
- Lectures, research notes, Dutch-American bibliography (Box 5)
  Includes notes, reprints, copies and Collection Development Tapes from the Suffolk Community College
- Dutch-American bibliography and note cards, microfilm, 1976 CLR file (Box 6)
- Research, consulting, professional, immigrant presses in America
  - Professional papers (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Foreign language research: America notes (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Arab (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Armenian (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Basque (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Belorussian (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bulgarian (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Carpatho-Rusyns (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Chinese (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Croats (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Czech (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Danes (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Dutch (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Estonians (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Finns (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Flemish (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - French (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - French (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - German (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Greek (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Hungarian (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Icelandic (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Italian (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Japanese (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Korean (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Latvian (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Lithuanian (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Norwegian (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Polish (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Portuguese (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Rumanian (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Russian (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Spanish, Cuban - Mexican - Puerto Rican (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Swedish (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Swiss (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Ukrainian (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Vietnamese (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Welsh (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Yiddish - Hebrew (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Yugoslav, Serbian - Slovak - Slovenian (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Suriname Reports (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Professional Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Preliminary Marketing Report for Research Publications Inc (Box 7, Folder 43)
- List of materials on The Detschnationale Volkspartei (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Pittsburgh use study (Box 7, Folder 45)
- The Collections of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Reviews in the Library Quarterly (Box 7, Folder 47)
- correspondence: NYHS (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Report: A Study on Materials Availability, Adelphi University (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Discussion on German Periodicals, by Charles Brown (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Edelman's Report on Collections (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Edelman publications (Box 8)
  Includes Logos, Library Journal, the Book Publishing Annual, Christian Book Publishing and Distribution and publications on eighteenth century English books, library research, computing etc. Also includes articles and interviews by Edelman
- Edelman and library publications (Box 9)
  Includes books on library planning, library search tools, library collection management, university libraries, library journals, computer innovation, obituaries etc.
- Planning, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Collection Analysis Project Explanatory Notes (Box 10, Folder 2)
- "Selection Methodology in Academic Libraries", paper presented at ALA preconference, 1977 June (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Report on the First Year's Activities Under the Cornell Mellon Project, 1978 Nov. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- General Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Acquisitions
  - Bangladesh (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - China (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - East Asia (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Japan (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Pakistan (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Singapore/Malaya (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Thailand, SE Asia (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - African Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Southeast Asia- Correspondence, 1960's-1980's (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - America's Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Arab & Australia Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Canada Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Austria & Egypt Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - European Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - France Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Germany Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Italy & Liechtenstein Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Netherlands Acquisitions, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Africana Studies & Res. Center, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Associated Scientific Publishing & Elsevier, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Harrassowitz, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Nijhoff, 1970's (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "A-B", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "C", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "D-G", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "H", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "I-L", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "M-Q", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "R", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "S", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - U.S. Acquisitions- "T-Z", 1970's (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Text by Petrus van Vlieren (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Cornell October "US" (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Kurt Wolff and Jacques Sciffrin (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Praeger (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Other immigrant publishers of note - in America (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Mauritus Dekker and Eric Proskauer (Box 10, Folder 42)
- The immigrants: Academic press (Box 10, Folder 43)
- Navigeren od de Stroomversnellingen van de Tijd (Box 10, Folder 44)
- Concept von een kroniek van de Elsevier Publishing Company (Box 10, Folder 45)
- Logos (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Wiley (Box 10, Folder 47)